Guide to the Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera 1700-1990 PR 31
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV: WEICHSEL TOBACCO COLLECTION
  - International tobacco companies (7 of 9) (Offsite-box WT 7, Box IV.19 - IV.21)
  - International tobacco companies (8 of 9) (Offsite-box WT 8, Box IV.22 - IV.24)
  - International tobacco companies (9 of 9) (Offsite-box WT 9, Box IV.25 - IV.26)
  - American tobacco companies - Cigarettes (1 of 4) (Offsite-box WT 9, Box IV.27)
  - American tobacco companies - Cigarettes (2 of 4) (Offsite-box WT 10, Box IV.28 - IV.30)
  - American tobacco companies - Cigarettes (3 of 4) (Offsite-box WT 11, Box IV.31 - IV.33)
  - American tobacco companies - Cigarettes (4 of 4) (Offsite-box WT 12, Box IV.34)
  - American tobacco companies - Cigars (1 of 2) (Offsite-box WT 12, Box IV.35 - IV.36)
  - American tobacco companies - Cigars (2 of 2) (Offsite-box WT 13, Box IV.37 - IV.39)
- Series V: PHOTOGRAPHS and FINE ART WORKS
  This series includes photographs, prints and paintings that are not related to advertising. Photographs include four gelatin silver prints of the conductors Arthur Rodzinsky, Bruno Walter Schlesinger, and Leopold Stokowski conducting various orchestras. Fine art prints contain the etchings, Sleighing in New York, by Henry Ziegler and Bob Hulse, Masterprinter, by Haydon Jones, and a Japanese print of Audubon discovering his drawings destroyed by mice. Also included are twelve Japanese paintings of tea growing and harvesting.
  - Photographs - Conductors/Orchestras (Offsite-box 137, Folder 1)
  - Fine Art Prints (Offsite-box 137, Folder 2)
  - Fine Art Prints - "Audubon Opening His Box of Watercolors Destroyed by Norway Rats", 1872–1877 (Offsite-box 137, Folder 3)
  - Japanese Paintings - Tea (Offsite-box 137, Folder 4-5)
- Series VI: PLAYING CARDS, 1843-1952
  This series includes sets playing cards, some of which are advertising a product.
  - Jubilaeums Bridge-Kort, Norway, 1937 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 1.1-1.2)
  - [Hamburg patterned deck] Germany, 1865 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Colorado River, USA, 1899 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 3.1-3.2)
  - New ERA Playing Cards No. 46, USA, 1896 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 4)
  - New York City Souvenir Playing Cards, USA, 1919 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 5.1-5.2)
  - Coca-Cola Airplane Spotter Playing Cards, USA, 1943 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 6)
  - Army and Navy #303, USA, 1886 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 7)
  - [Lawrence and Cohen], USA, undated (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 8)
  - [Dougherty], USA, 1875 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 9)
  - Diamond Crystal Salt, USA, 1946 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 10)
  - Tally-Ho Playing Cards No. 9, undated (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 11.1-11.2)
  - I Like Ike, 1952 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 12)
  - [The United Shield stands for quality...], USA, undated (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 13)
  - ESP cards for testing Extra Sensory Perception, 1937 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 14)
  - Sehr Feine Aufschlagkarten, Austria, 1889 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 15)
  - [French Teaching Cards], France, undated (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 16)
  - Authors, USA, undated (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 17)
  - Authors, USA, undated (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 18)
  - Maud, undated (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 19)
  - Who Killed Cock Robin?, USA, undated (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 20)
  - Dr. Busby, the Improved and Illustrated Game, USA, 1843 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 21)
  - The Improved Geographical Cards, USA, 1899 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 22)
  - [Bridge Scoring Sheet], USA, 1932 (Offsite-box 140, Box 138, Folder 23)
- Series VII: SPEAKEASY CARDS, 1920s
  This series is comprised of speakeasy cards advertising illicit bars that operated during the years of Prohibition.
  - Speakeasy Cards, A-Z (Offsite-box 140, Box 139)
- Series VIII: WORLD WAR II ARMY-NAVY E AWARDS EPHEMERA, 1942-1945
  This series consists chiefly of printed materials related to the Army-Navy "E" Award, or the Excellence in War Production Award. The Army Navy "E" Award was an honor presented to top performers of the civilian war industry during World War II. It was only given to about 4 percent of the homefront industry during the wartime years.
  The "E" Awards program began in July 1942, and was meant to encourage production of materials needed for the United States'complete military mobilization effort. The award consisted of a pennant for the plant and pins for all employees. The pennant was triangular swallowtail with a white border, with a capital E within a yellow wreath of oak and laurel leaves on a vertical divided blue and red background. ARMY is on the red background and NAVY on the blue background.
  The presentation of the E Award was made in a formal ceremony that was preceded by issuance of printed invitations and programs. These programs, from a wide array of companies and industries across the United States, make up the bulk of this series.
  Arrangement
  Material is arranged alphabetically by company name.
  - Companies A-B, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box VIII.1)
  - Companies C-D, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box VIII.2)
  - Companies E-F, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box VIII.3)
  - Companies G-I, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box VIII.4)
  - Companies J-L, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box VIII.5)
  - Companies M-N, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box VIII.6)
  - Companies O-R, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box VIII.7)
  - Companies S-T, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box VIII.8)
  - Companies U-Z, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box VIII.9)